所以现在让我很快地告诉你
So now let me just very quickly show you
我们如何在 CSS 中为元素添加尺寸
how we can add dimensions to elements in CSS
使用高度和宽度属性。
using the height and the width property.
让我们再一次，从这里的侧元素开始
And let's once again, start with our side element down here
稍后将成为我们的侧边栏。
which at some point later will be our sidebar.
所以它不应该那么宽
And so it shouldn't be as wide
相反，我们只想要 500 像素宽。
and instead we only wanted to be 500 pixels wide.
所以我们可以简单地来到我们的元素
So we can simply come here to our element
并将宽度指定为 500 像素。
and specify the width as 500 pixels.
就这样，
And just like that,
现在我们的侧边元素只有 500 像素宽。
now our side element is only 500 pixels wide.
所以比页面的其余部分窄得多。
So a lot more narrow than the rest of the page.
好的。
Okay.
非常简单，非常简单。
So very easy, very straightforward.
那就是宽度属性。
That is the width property.
让我们尝试另一个。
Let's try another one.
所以实际上让我们现在试试高度。
So actually let's try height now.
我在主标题中这样做。
And I'm doing that here in the main header.
所以在这里，让我们设置高度
So here, let's set the height
比方说80像素。
to let's say 80 pixels.
好的。
All right.
现在你看到它是如何在这里增加的，对吧？
And now you saw how it increased here, right?
现在让我们在这里实际检查这个标题。
Now let's actually inspect this header here.
所以不是链接，而是整个标题元素，对吗？
So not the link, but the entire header element, right?
如果我们在这里查看盒子模型，
And if we check out the box model down here,
所以这有点小
so this is all a bit small
但是没关系。
but nevermind.
所以你可以看到这里我们实际上有 80 个像素
So you can see that here we actually have the 80 pixels
我们刚刚指定的，对吧？
that we just specified, right?
然后最重要的是，
And then top of that,
我们在顶部和底部有 20 个像素。
we have the 20 pixels to the top and to the bottom.
所以元素的完整最终大小
And so the complete final size of the element
其实不是我们这里指定的80像素，
is actually not the 80 pixels that we specified here,
但它是80加20加20，也就是120像素。
but it is 80 plus 20 plus 20, which is 120 pixels.
所以这正是盒子模型的默认行为
So that is exactly that default behavior of the box model
我之前提到的
that I mentioned before
在我看来，这根本没有任何意义。
and that in my opinion, doesn't make any sense at all.
但同样，我们稍后会解决这个问题。
But again, we will fix that a little bit later.
现在很重要
For now it is important
了解盒子模型最初是如何工作的。
to learn how the box model actually works originally.
同样是这个元素的真实高度
And so again the real height of this element
不是我们这里指定的80，
is not the 80 that we specified here,
但是我们必须添加填充
but we would then have to add the padding
到顶部和底部。
to the top and bottom.
好的。
Okay.
现在，您也可能在这里注意到的一件事是
Now, one thing that you also might have noticed here is
内容，所以这里的文字，
that the content, so the text here,
不只是神奇地垂直居中
doesn't just magically get vertically centered inside
这个标题元素。
of this header element.
所以它实际上之前是垂直居中的，
So it actually was vertically centered before,
但这仅仅是因为我们应用了相同的填充
but that was simply because we had applied the same padding
到双方。
to both of the sides.
但现在没有了。
But now not anymore.
我的意思是，我们仍然在两边有相同的填充，
I mean, we still do have the same padding on both sides,
但现在我们在这里有了另一个高度。
but now we have this other height here.
所以现在底部的空间
And so now the space that's at the bottom
不再是顶部的空间。
is no longer the space that's at the top.
实际上，这并不是很简单
And actually, it's not really straightforward
将其垂直居中，
to center this vertically,
当然，我们稍后会学习如何。
but of course we will learn how a little bit later.
好的。
Okay.
所以让我们关闭它。
So let's close it.
现在让我们最后真正谈谈这张图片。
And now let's actually finally talk about this image.
所以到目前为止，它一直原封不动地坐在这里，
So up until this point, it has been sitting here untouched,
但现在让我们选择它并实际调整它的大小。
but now let's select it and let's actually size it.
为此，
And for that,
让我们给它一个类，以便我们可以选择它。
let's give it a class so that we can then select it.
所以...
So...
这里就是这个。
It is this one here.
所以类'帖子图像'让我们说。
So class of 'posts-image' let's say.
复制它然后...
Copy it and then...
好吧，让我们说...
Well, let's say...
实际上在最底层的某个地方。
somewhere here at the very bottom actually.
所以这只是一个演示，所以我把它放在这里。
So this here was just a demo, so I'm putting it here.
现在让我们在这里指定宽度。
And now let's specify the width here.
所以其实很常见
So it is actually very common
在 CSS 中而不是在 HTML 中调整图像大小，就像我们所做的那样。
to size images in CSS and not in HTML like we did.
实际上很多时候，我们甚至从不指定宽度
Actually many times, we never even specify the width
HTML 中的图像，但仅在 CSS 中。
of images in HTML but only in CSS.
现在第一次来这里，
Now here for the first time,
我不会使用像素长度。
I will not use length in pixels.
我的意思是，我可以。
I mean, I could.
现在，假设为 800 像素。
For now, let's say 800 pixels.
所以...
And so...
好吧，看起来它实际上是错误的图像
Well, that looks like it actually was the wrong image
我们在这里选择的。
that we selected here.
所以这门课当然应该是这个。
So the class should be of course on this one.
所以现在看起来是正确的。
And so now that looks correct.
这就是我们在那里指定的 800
And so that's 800 that we specified there
现在确实覆盖了这 500 个。
did now override this 500.
但是，这里的这 200 个仍然存在。
However, this 200 here is still in place.
这就是为什么宽高比现在是
And that's why the aspect ratio is now
就像完全坏了一样，对吧？
like completely broken, right?
所以这看起来不再正确了。
So this doesn't look correct anymore.
它被拉伸到宽度。
It's way stretched to the width.
所以为了解决这个问题，
And so in order to fix that,
如果我们必须在 HTML 中指定高度，
in case we do have to height specified in HTML,
我们需要做的是将高度设置为“自动”。
what we need to do is to then set the height to 'auto'.
这样就可以解决它
And so that will then fix it
我们将把纵横比放回原来的样子。
and we'll put the aspect ratio back to the original.
好的。
Okay.
但同样，指定高度
But again, specifying the height
并将其设置为 auto 只是必要的
and setting it to auto is only necessary
如果之前已经在 HTML 中指定了该高度。
if that height is already specified before in HTML.
如果我们不这样做，
In case we don't do that,
所以如果我们没有在 HTML 中指定任何图像尺寸，
so in case we don't specify any image dimensions in HTML,
那么如果我们使用 CSS 设置高度或宽度，
then if we set the height or the width using CSS,
另一个会按顺序自动适应
the other one will automatically adapt in order
考虑图像的原始纵横比。
to account for the original aspect ratio of the image.
例如，如果我们将其设置为 300，
So for example if we set this to 300,
那么它会变得非常小，对吗？
then it would become really small, right?
但现在，正如我所说，
But now, as I said,
让我们第一次真正远离像素
let's actually move away from pixels for the first time
并使用百分比。
and use percentages.
所以我可以这样说宽度，
So I can say the width like this,
所以'100%'。
so '100%'.
通常对于这样的宽度测量，
And usually for a width measurement like this,
百分比通常是百分比
the percentage is usually the percentage
父容器的宽度。
of the width of the parent container.
所以帖子图片的父级是标题
So the parent of the post image is the header
这个标题基本上是页面的整个宽度。
and this header is basically the entire width of the page.
对？
Right?
所以如果我说 100%
And so if I say with of 100%,
那么这个图像现在应该是整个页面的宽度。
then this image should now be the width of the entire page.
事实上，这正是我们得到的。
And indeed that is exactly what we get.
所以这件事的特别之处在于 现在
And so what's special about this is that now
当我们改变窗口的大小时，
as we change the size of the window,
那么图像的大小将始终保持在 100%。
then the size of the image will always stay at 100%.
好的。
Okay.
因为那总是父容器的大小。
Because that is always the size of the parent container.
当然，我们可以将其设置为其他内容，
Of course we could set it to something else,
像父容器大小的一半。
like half of the size of the parent container.
仍然会发生的是
And what would still happen is that
当我们改变父容器的大小时，
as we changed the size of the parent container,
那么图像的大小也会适应。
then the size of the image would also adapt.
好的。
Okay.
这将变得非常非常重要
And this is something that will become very, very important
一旦我们开始谈论构建响应式网站，
once we start talking about building responsive websites,
所以适应屏幕宽度的网站。
so websites that adapt to the screen width.
好的。
Okay.
但是让我们把它放回100%，
But let's put it back to 100%,
这是我们最初想要的。
which is what we originally wanted.
有了这个，我认为我们实际上已经完成了
And with that, I think we are actually done
设置一些高度和一些宽度，至少现在是这样。
with setting some heights and some width, at least for now.